

DEEPAK DHASMANA

SENIOR PRODUCTION ENGINEER

H.No. 75, Vandana enclave, Khora colony, Ghaziabad, Uttar Pradesh Pin: 201301

Mob: 7291025486

Email: deepakdhasmana70@gmail.com LinkedIn: deepak-dhasmana-4471895a

CAREER SUMMARY

To obtain a position that allows me to utilize my skills in production engineering and operation. With work experience of seven years in various manufacturing industries like packaging machines, printing and allied machines, pneumatic equipment. I have gained substantial product development knowledge along with manufacturing process.

QUALIFICATIONS

Diploma in mechanical engineering	Higher secondary	Secondary
G. B. Pant polytechnic Okhla, Delhi Aggregate 74% with distinction Completed in 2013	Govt. Boys Sr. Secondary school New kondli, Delhi Aggregate 53% marks Completed in 2009	Govt. Co-ed Secondary school Vashundhara enclave, Delhi Aggregate 80% marks Completed in 2007

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Production Engineer

Shubham flexible packaging machines pvt. ltd Faridabad, Haryana

May 2019 - till date

Job responsibilities:

- Leading and managing team of 4 supervisors, 40 skilled fitters in assembly shop along with 1 foreman, 10 operators and 4 helpers in tool room.
- Making daily, weekly and monthly plan as accordance to dispatch plan.
- Assign manpower for sub assembly, trial, dispatch and spare assembly.
- Process improvement by making SOP and work instructions and implement them in assembly and tool room.
- Reduce assembly rejection and rework by design implementation through ECR.
- Follow up for shortages with PPC, purchase, M/shop and fabrication to ensure material received on time.
- Maintaining assembly checklist, packing list, gantt chart of machine, tool room production report, assembly rework data and skill matrix of employees.
- Any other task given by management.

Junior Engineer Assembly

Uflex limited (Engineering division)
Noida. Uttar Pradesh

Sept 2016 – April 2019

Job responsibilities:

- Managed team of 2 foremen, 24 skilled fitters and 10 helpers.
- Made daily, weekly and monthly plan as accordance to dispatch plan.
- Assigned manpower for sub-assembly, frame erection, trial and dispatch activities.
- Issued components, tools and consumables for daily assembly activities.
- Followed up for shortages with PPC, purchase, M/shop and sheet metal shop.
- Resolve fitment problems by coordinating with QC and design.
- BOM correction in Oracle ERP with design.

Junior Engineer Assembly

SMC Pneumatics India pvt. ltd.

Noida, Uttar Pradesh

Feb 2015 – Sept 2016

Job responsibilities:

- Managed a team of 5 technicians in assembly shop.
- Issued job card to team members along with inventory components through store.
- Arranged machined components as per job card requirement.
- Insure job card received completed on the same day by aligning manpower on various lines.
- Reduced line rejection by using SOP and proper work instructions.
- Maintained 5s and safety on the shop floor.

Diploma Engineer Trainee

Escorts auto products limited Faridabad, Haryana

July 2013 – Feb 2015

Job responsibilities:

- Worked on sock absorber assembly line on various work stations (Piston assembly, piston rod crimping, oil filling, pressing and crimping).
- Operated Fanuc 3-axis vmc machines in TFF machine shop.

SKILLS

- Production planning
- Manpower management
- Kai-zen
- 55
- SOP

INDUSTRIAL TRAINING

Completed four weeks industrial training (1st July 2012 to 30th July 2012) from Delhi Transport Corporation's central workshop located in Okhla, Delhi.

IMPROVEMENT PROJECTS

- Established new assembly station for conveyor assembly with automated tools and testing arrangement at Shubham Pack (Faridabad plant).
- Established new assembly station for roller assembly with automated assembly tools and testing arrangement at Uflex (Noida plant).
- Established fixed place for jig and fixtures and movable tool box for assembly tools in newly developed cylinder assembly line at SMC (Noida plant).

ACHIEVEMENTS

- GMP award in 2018 at Uflex limited.
- Kushal Star of the month in 2019 at Uflex limited.
- Kai-zen award in 2015 at SMC Pneumatics India.

HOBBIES

- Watching infotainment programs and documentaries
- Cooking food
- Playing badminton

PERSONNEL DETAILS

- Father's Name: Harish chandra
- Date of birth: 15/08/1992
- Gender: Male
- Marital status: Unmarried
- Religion: Hindu Nationality: Indian
- Language known: English & Hindi

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above information is correct and complete to the best of my knowledge.

Date:

(Deepak Dhasmana) Place: